Debabrata Saha

Specialist Senior Engineer

Contact

Address

Kolkata, WB, 700013

Phone

9874345299

E-mail

debabrata18992@gmail.co m

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/debabrata-saha-9a6112a

www

https://debabrata23.github.i o/MyWebsiteProfile/

Skills

SharePoint online and SPFX

Advanced

SharePoint onpremises

Intermediate

0365 Development

Upper intermediate

Powerapps

Advanced

PowerAutomate online

Advanced

Having an experience of 6.6 years with forward-thinking Software Engineer with background working productively in dynamic environments. Fluent in Type and Type programming languages used to develop software within Industry. Proud team player focused on achieving project objectives with speed and accuracy.

Work History

2022-01 -Current

Specialist Software Engineer

LTI, Kolkata, West Bengal

- Responsible in architechting the application backend in Azure SQL
- Creating views and procedure in SQL for power apps
- Automating various approval flows using power automate
- Involved in requirement gathering and suggesting flexible and user friendly application methodology development

2021-05 -2022-01

Senior Software Engineer

EY, Bangalore, Karnataka

- Responsible in developing Commercial application for internal client of EY
- creating application customized and list view extension in SharePoint framework
- Creating spfx webpart using React js and redux
- Building PCF component for one of esteemed client
- Involved in designing the page using Fluent UI and html css

2019-11 -2021-04

Technology Consultant

PwC, Bangalore, Karnataka

- Designed REST calls using React to streamline user interface performance.
- Maintained high-level expertise in React state management strategies.
- Designed and implemented dynamic content and web-server applications using best practices.

2019-02 -2019-10

Senior Associate Consultant

Power virtual agent
Intermediate
React Js
Upper intermediate
Redux
Intermediate
Javascript
Upper intermediate
CSOM
Upper intermediate
JSOM
Upper intermediate
PNP JS
Intermediate

Intermediate

REST API

Mindtree, Bangalore, Karnataka

- Leveraged built-in and hand-crafted development techniques using native SharePoint technologies or designed and developed user-friendly end product for custom solutions.
- Participated in system development life cycle from requirements analysis through system implementation.
- Solved design problems and implemented attractive design using creative methods.
- Involved in SharePoint 2013 support using jQuery and rest API and also involved in end of end redevelopment of a SharePoint 2013 site in sharepoint online using spfx

2016-11 - **Software Engineer**

Acuvate Software PVT LTD, Hyderabad , Telengana

- Solved design problems and implemented attractive design using creative methods.
- Designed and implemented dynamic content and web-server applications using best practices.

2016-04 -2016-10 Contractor

CMC, Kolkata, West Bengal

 Created optimal technical solutions to user needs with in-depth system analysis.

Education

2008-02 -

2009-02

Lycee - Kolkata

2011-04 - B.Tech : ECE

2015-07

Narula Institute of Technology - Kolkata

2010-03 - CBSE 12: Science

Apeejay School - Kolkata

ICSE: General

Certifications

2022-06

Microsoft Certified Power Platform fundamental PL 900